<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<page>
	<title strClassViewPageTitle="span2 cfuwWhite text-right containerPageTitle rotateGoLeft transitionIn">HOME</title>
	<paragraphs catagory="home">
		<paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="bold">A HISTORY OF CFUW SASKATOON INC.</heading>
            <content strClassContent="bold">1918 - 2014</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">HELLO WORLD</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">On May 8, 1918, fifteen women met at what is now known as Nutana Collegiate.  The result of this meeting. and previous informal discussions of various progressive ideas, was the formation of the University Women's Club of Saskatoon.  Membership was to be open to women graduates of accredited universities.  At this Charter meeting, they agreed to affiliate with the local Council of Women, a relationship that continues until today.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">Two weeks after the Club was organized, Canadian women received the right to vote in federal elections and to stand for seats in parliament.  It would take eleven more years to October 18, 1929 for the Judicial Committee of the Privy Council of Great Britain to declare women to be "persons" in a constitutional context.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">The Club's objective was to provide intellectual stimulation through the study of educational, social and community issues.  Membership fees were $1.00.  The Club members served President Murray in a consulting capacity regarding the best way to encourage young women to proceed to University studies.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">Very early on, contributions began to assist female students at the University of Saskatchewan.  A Scholarship Committee was created in 1919.  Informative programs were presented regularly.  In 1919, the Club voted to enter into association with the Canadian Federation of University Women and the International Federation of University women.  Scholarship contributions were made nationally</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">During the war and post-war period, programs continued and a nucleus of  study groups was maintained by club members.  In 1940, the Club decided to award an annual scholarship and the first award was $100.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">The 25th Anniversary celebration in 1943 saw the Club broadening its scope with the receipt of the first resolution for discussion from the Canadian Federation of University women.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">In the 1950's, a non-stop pattern for the future began.  The first bequest to the Club was received from an estate and the $300 was awarded to second and third year students.  1957 saw the first Book Fair and the 1st National CFUW Conference.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">During the 60's, focus continued to emphasize social issues. Issues of interest were education of aboriginal peoples, drug addiction, T.V. credit courses, water pollution, tax inequities, equal pay for equal work and opposition to discriminative education.  Special study groups focused on  Education, Status of Women, and International Relations.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">Book fairs were initiated along with other fund raising.  As book sales increased, so did contributions that included the music festival, school art project, the regional science fair and the National Charitable Trust Scholarship Fund.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">Social activities formed a pattern: Fall Membership Tea, Scholarship Winner Celebration, Christmas Social, January Luncheon Featuring, Resolution Discussion and Annual General Meeting and Banquet.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">The CFUW Scholarship Fund became incorporated. In the mid-nineties, the Saskatoon Club submitted a resolution to the national CFUW body under the title "Stopping the Proliferation of Gambling in Canada".  Many other advocacy efforts occupied the membership.  Letters were written and representations made before commissions and hearings.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">In the 2000s, our annual Book Sale grew exponentially.  It was a challenge to find locations for collection, storage and selling our books. The Book Sale continues to be our most lucrative fund raiser.  With the help of our book committee, the generous volunteers and the support of our community, many young women from the University of Saskatchewan have been awarded scholarships.</content>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph>
            <heading strClassHeading="displayNone">&#160;</heading>
            <content strClassContent="">In 2008, Saskatoon celebrated it's 90th anniversary.  2018...100 years!</content>
        </paragraph>
	</paragraphs>
</page>