<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<page>
    <title strClassViewPageTitle="span2 cfuwWhite text-right containerPageTitle rotateGoLeft transitionIn">SCHOLARSHIPS</title>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<paragraph0 strClass0="">The Canadian Federation of University Women/Saskatoon Inc. has been offering scholarships to female students at the University of Saskatchewan since 1940.  Over $300,000 has been awarded since the programs' inception.  Funding in support of these scholarships comes from members, families and friends of members, and bequests.  Our largest annual infusion of money comes from our gigantic fall book sale.</paragraph0>
			<paragraph1 strClass1="">We offer up to eleven Undergraduate and six Graduate Scholarships.</paragraph1>
		</section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="" class="inline">The Undergraduate Scholarships of $1,500 each are offered annually to female students in any field who have maintained an average of 75% or higher. The awards will be made only to full-time students at the University of Saskatchewan. Preference will be given to students working on their first degree.</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1  strClass1="bold inline">The application deadline for the Undergraduate scholarship is May 31st</paragraph1>  
            <paragraph2  strClass2="inline">and applicants will be informed in July or August.  There are additional requirements specific to each of the eleven scholarships, please see the detailed information further down this page.</paragraph2>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">&#160;</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="inline">The five $1,500 Graduate Scholarships (</paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="inline bold">Jean Murray Memorial, Dorothea Friebel, Benee, CFUW Saskatoon Inc.</paragraph2>
            <paragraph3 strClass3="inline">, and </paragraph3>
            <paragraph4 strClass4="inline bold">Jacqueline McKenzie Newstead Scholarships</paragraph4>
            <paragraph5 strClass5="inline">) are offered to female students in any field of study who have completed at least one year of course work, have an approved thesis or project proposal, and are not recipients of any substantive scholarships.</paragraph5>  
            <paragraph6 strClass6="inline bold">The application deadline for the Graduate scholarships is February 1, 2016.</paragraph6>
            <paragraph7 strClass7="">&#160;</paragraph7>
            <link strClassAnchor="block bold pdf" href="http://students.usask.ca/documents/awards/grad/cfuw.pdf">Graduate Scholarship Application Form</link>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">&#160;</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="inline">The $5,000 </paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="inline bold">Newstead Doctoral Scholarship</paragraph2>
            <paragraph3 strClass3="inline">is offered to a female student who has completed all the course requirements, including comprehensive exams, has the approval of the Ethics Committee, and is well advanced in the writing of her thesis or research project.  The application deadline for the Doctoral Scholarship is February 1, 2016</paragraph3>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">&#160;</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="inline">There are additional requirements specific to each of the six graduate scholarships, please see the detailed information further down this page.</paragraph1>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="h3">Detailed Information</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="h3">Undergraduate Scholarships</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">Additional requirements:</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="bullet">The Annie B. and Isabel Shaw Scholarship is available to a student entering her second year of university studies.</paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="bullet">The Marie I. Gillespie Scholarship is awarded to a mature woman who has completed at least one year of university, with preference given to a parent.</paragraph2>
            <paragraph3 strClass3="bullet">The Mary Hallett Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least one year of university studies and needs financial support.</paragraph3>
            <paragraph4 strClass4="bullet">The Carolyn Hartney Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least one year of university studies, needs financial support, but is not likely to receive numerous or major awards.
            </paragraph4>
            <paragraph5 strClass5="bullet">The Jean Bayer Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least two years of university studies.</paragraph5>
            <paragraph6 strClass6="bullet">The Harriet Kaplan Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least two years of university studies.</paragraph6>
            <paragraph7 strClass7="bullet">The Rowles Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least two years of university studies and demonstrates financial need.</paragraph7>
            <paragraph8 strClass8="bullet">The Grace Swanson Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least two years of university studies and demonstrates financial need.</paragraph8>
            <paragraph9 strClass9="bullet">The Vivian Morton Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least two years of university studies and demonstrates financial need. Preference will be given to a mature candidate who is continuing her studies after an interruption (in education) of several years.</paragraph9>
            <paragraph10 strClass10="bullet">The Jacqueline McKenzie Newstead Scholarship is available to a student who has completed three or more years of university and demonstrates financial need. Given similar qualifications, preference will be given to a single parent.</paragraph10>
            <paragraph11 strClass11="bullet">The Florence E. Bennee Fine Arts Scholarship is new in 2012.  It is open to a student in Fine Arts studies (Drama, Music or Art &#038; Art History).  It is available to both male and female applicants, at the request of the donor.</paragraph11>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">&#160;</paragraph0>
            <link strClassAnchor="pdf bold block" href="http://students.usask.ca/pdf/awards/CFUW_App%20and_Release_2014.pdf">Undergraduate Scholarship Application Form (on University of Saskatchewan web site)</link>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="h3">Graduate Scholarships</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">Additional requirements:</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">These awards are directed towards women completing their degrees. They will be awarded to female graduate students based on academic excellence and demonstrated financial need. The students must have completed at least one year of course work and have an approved thesis or project proposal. </paragraph0>
        </section> 
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="bullet">Dr. Jean Murray Memorial Scholarship; Dorothea Friebel Scholarship; Bennee Scholarship; CFUW Saskatoon Inc. Scholarship - These are intended to be used to cover expenses associated with the thesis completion.</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="bullet">The Jacqueline McKenzie Newstead Scholarship may be used for any expenses incurred in completing the degree. At the request of the donor, given otherwise similar qualifications, preference may be given to a single mother.</paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="bullet">The Newstead Doctoral Scholarship is awarded to a female Ph.D. student who has completed all the required courses, including the comprehensive exams for the degree, and be well advanced in the writing of the thesis. Given similar qualifications, preference is given to a student who demonstrates financial need, or whose research is of potential benefit to women in society.</paragraph2>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="h3">Application Procedure:</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="">The student applies by sending the application form (use the link below) to the College of Graduate Studies and Research along with:</paragraph1>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="bulletNumbered">A one-page letter of intent. The letter should include the title of the thesis or project, description of the research (in terms that are easily understood by a non-technical reader), research methodology, objectives, motivation for embarking on research, and professional goals upon completion of the work;</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="bulletNumbered">A list of current University Scholarships and distinctions won, including amount, tenure, and source;</paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="bulletNumbered">The source and amount of monetary support, including research grants, stipends, teaching assistantships, lab technician wages, and also other sources of income;</paragraph2>
            <paragraph3 strClass3="bulletNumbered">A list of publications, conferences and poster presentations, and related work and/or volunteer experiences;</paragraph3>
            <paragraph4 strClass4="bulletNumbered">A letter of recommendation from the research supervisor outlining the student's personal qualities and past achievements and potential. It should state the student's current progress in the program and estimated completion date, and the financial support that is being provided to the student. This letter should be sent directly from the department to the College of Graduate Studies and Research.</paragraph4>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">In accordance with Canada Revenue Agency regulations, Social Insurance Numbers will be required from all scholarship winners and their applications will be retained by CFUW Saskatoon Inc. for six years.</paragraph0>
        </section>     
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="" id="admissions_how_to_apply">Website: Graduate Scholarship Application Form (on University of Saskatchewan web site)</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="">Mailing Address for Graduate Scholarship applications:</paragraph0>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="increaseIndention">College of Graduate Studies and Research,</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="increaseIndention">University of Saskatchewan,</paragraph1>
            <paragraph2 strClass2="increaseIndention">ATTN: Awards Officer,</paragraph2>
            <paragraph3 strClass3="increaseIndention">Rm C180, Administration Bldg,</paragraph3>
            <paragraph4 strClass4="increaseIndention">105 Administration Pl,</paragraph4>
            <paragraph5 strClass5="increaseIndention marginBottomIncrease">Saskatoon, SK  S7N 5A2</paragraph5>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="marginBottomZero">Phone: 306-966-5760</paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="marginBottomZero">Email: gradstudies.awards@usask.ca</paragraph1>
        </section>
        <section>
            <paragraph0 strClass0="bold inline">Deadline: </paragraph0>
            <paragraph1 strClass1="inline">February 01, 2016</paragraph1>
        </section>
	</sections>
</page>