<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<page>
	<title>SCHOLARSHIPS</title>
	<members>
		<member>
			<position>The Canadian Federation of University Women/Saskatoon Inc. has been offering scholarships to female students at the University of Saskatchewan since 1940.  Over $300,000 has been awarded since the programs' inception.  Funding in support of these scholarships comes from members, families and friends of members, and bequests.  Our largest annual infusion of money comes from our gigantic fall book sale.</position>
			<name>We offer up to eleven Undergraduate and six Graduate Scholarships.</name>
		</member>
        <member>
            <position>The Undergraduate Scholarships of $1,500 each are offered annually to female students in any field who have maintained an average of 75% or higher. The awards will be made only to full-time students at the University of Saskatchewan. Preference will be given to students working on their first degree. The application deadline for the Undergraduate scholarship is May 31st and applicants will be informed in July or August.  There are additional requirements specific to each of the eleven scholarships, please see the detailed information further down this page.</position>
            <name>The five $1,750 Graduate Scholarships (Jean Murray Memorial, Dorothea Friebel, Benee, CFUW Saskatoon Inc., and Jacqueline McKenzie Newstead Scholarships) are offered to female students in any field of study who have completed at least one year of course work, have an approved thesis or project proposal, and are not recipients of any substantive scholarships.  The application deadline for the Graduate scholarships is February 2, 2015.</name>
        </member>
        <member>
            <position>The $5,000 Newstead Doctoral Scholarship is offered to a female student who has completed all the course requirements, including comprehensive exams, has the approval of the Ethics Committee, and is well advanced in the writing of her thesis or research project.  The application deadline for the Doctoral Scholarship is February 2, 2015</position>
            <name>There are additional requirements specific to each of the six graduate scholarships, please see the detailed information further down this page.</name>
        </member>
        <member>
            <position>Detailed Information</position>
            <name>Undergraduate Scholarships</name>
        </member>
        <member>
            <position>Additional requirements:</position>
            <name>The Annie B. and Isabel Shaw Scholarship is available to a student entering her second year of university studies.</name>
        </member>
        <member>
            <position>The Marie I. Gillespie Scholarship is awarded to a mature woman who has completed at least one year of university, with preference given to a parent.</position>
            <name>The Mary Hallett Scholarship is available to a student who has completed at least one year of university studies and needs financial support.</name>
        </member>
	</members>
</page>